Okay then, so now we've got Claude code set up and running inside this project, I would like to start using it to make some changes to the code and working on new components.But before we do that, it's always a good idea when you're starting to use the forward slash init command to initialize a Claude.md file inside the project root.And when we do this, Claude scans the entire code base, it looks at the folder structure, how we style the application, any state management we use, et cetera, the whole should
好的，現在我們已經在這個專案中設定好並啟動 Claude Code，我想開始用它來修改程式碼並開發新的元件。但在那之前，建議先執行 /init 指令，在專案根目錄初始化一個 CLAUDE.md 檔案。執行後，Claude 會掃描整個程式碼庫，查看資料夾結構、應用程式的樣式方式、使用的狀態管理等等，整個程式碼庫都會被
exam so that it gets a good feel for the project, where everything goes and how it should code new features in the future.Then it summarizes all of that and it dumps the information into a Claude.md file in a structured human readable format.Then whenever we have an active session with Claude code to either ask about our project code or to make changes to the code, it uses that Claude.md file as context and guidance.It's almost like a mini documentation of your code for Claude to use
全面審視，讓它對專案有個完整的了解，知道各個部分的位置以及未來應如何撰寫新功能。然後它會整理所有這些資訊，以結構化且人類可讀的格式彙整到 CLAUDE.md 檔案中。往後每當我們與 Claude Code 開啟作業階段，無論是詢問專案程式碼或進行修改，它都會使用這個 CLAUDE.md 檔案作為上下文和指引，就像是為 Claude 準備的一份迷你專案說明文件，用來
whenever it's trying to figure out the best way to implement something or to give feedback.So then I'm going to press enter now to run this command and see what it comes up with.
幫助它在嘗試找出實作某功能的最佳方式或提供回饋時作為參考。現在我要按 Enter 執行這個指令，看看它會產生什麼結果。
And you can see as it's doing this, it's created a little to-do list for itself.It's going to explore the repository, analyze the package.json and the source code.It's going to check for existing documentation files.And then finally it's going to create this Claude.md file at the bottom.And you can see that it'skind of checking things off as it does it.So it's really good to see the progress of what it's doing.In between all that, it's reading the files, it's searching for things.So yeah, it's doing a real extensive kind of task.
你可以看到，在執行的過程中，它為自己建立了一個小小的待辦清單：探索儲存庫、分析 package.json 和原始碼、檢查現有的說明文件，最後在底部建立 CLAUDE.md 檔案。你可以看到它在完成每個步驟時一一打勾，很方便追蹤進度。在這整個過程中，它在讀取檔案、搜尋資訊，確實是一項相當全面且繁重的任務。
All right then, so now once it's done all that, you can see it's created this plan.And if we scroll right to the bottom, it's asking us, Do you want to create this Claude.md file?And I'm going to select yes.So then it goes ahead to create that file, which we can see in the root of the project directory now.So let's open that up over here and see what it looks like.So you can see this file provides guidance to Claude code when working with code in this repository.
好了，完成所有步驟後，你可以看到它已建立了這個計劃。捲動到最底部，它會詢問我們：「是否要建立這個 CLAUDE.md 檔案？」我選擇是。接著它就會建立該檔案，現在可以在專案根目錄中看到它了。讓我們打開它看看長什麼樣子。你可以看到，這個檔案為 Claude Code 在這個儲存庫中處理程式碼時提供了指引。
So it's got some different development commands that it's found from the package.json thing right here.It's got an architecture overview.So it says what it is briefly, it's a Next.js 15 blog application.You can see the different things we're using inside it.So React 19, Tailwind, V4, VTest, et cetera.We've got a project structure, which is quite nice.So it knows that when it's creating new files, hopefully where to put those files.We've got some data architecture right here.
它從 package.json 中找到了一些不同的開發指令，還有架構概覽，簡述了這是一個 Next.js 15 部落格應用程式，你可以看到其中使用的各種技術：React 19、Tailwind V4、Vitest 等等。還有專案結構說明，這相當好用，讓它在建立新檔案時知道應該放在哪裡。這裡還有一些資料架構的說明。
So it knows that we're using HighGraph for the content.And down here we've got information about the styling.We've got a testing setup right here and some additional development notes as well.So this is quite comprehensive.It gives Claude Code now a good guide as to what we're doing.Whenever we make changes, it can use this guide.
它知道我們使用 Hygraph 來管理內容。下面還有樣式設定的說明、測試設置以及一些額外的開發備注。整體相當全面，為 Claude Code 提供了一份清楚的指南，讓它了解我們在做什麼，每次進行修改時都可以參考這份指南。
Now, since I'd already started this project before Claude Code got involved, it was able to scan my existing codebase and pick up on a lot of things so it could make a detailed Claude file based on the code I've got.But if you're starting with a brand new project with virtually no setup files or code, then it's going to have much less to work with.The Claude.md file is probably not going to have much in it.
由於我在引入 Claude Code 之前就已經開始這個專案了，它能夠掃描現有的程式碼庫並掌握很多資訊，從而根據我已有的程式碼建立一份詳細的 CLAUDE.md 檔案。但如果你是從一個幾乎沒有設定檔或程式碼的全新專案開始，它能參考的資料就少得多，CLAUDE.md 檔案可能不會有太多內容。
But in that case, you can manually go into the file and edit it yourself to outline any high-level project structures you're going to put in place, any tools, packages or frameworks you're going to be using.your code style preferences, and just basically an overall summary of the application.You can just update it as you go then.That last bit is important, whether you're starting with a new project or an existing one, because you should keep this file updated if you change your file structure, any packages you use, or anything else outlined inside this file.
在那種情況下，你可以手動進入檔案自行編輯，概述你計劃建立的高層專案結構、將使用的工具、套件或框架、你的程式碼風格偏好，以及應用程式的整體摘要，然後隨著開發進度逐步更新。最後這一點非常重要，無論是新專案還是既有專案：如果你更改了資料夾結構、使用的套件，或檔案中記載的任何其他內容，都應該隨時更新這個檔案。
If you don't, then Claude Code might not automatically pick up on those changes, and it could go off in a completely different direction when you ask it to do something.Anyway, this claude.md file now gets added to the session context automatically, so that Claude can refer to it when it makes changes, and you'll find that keeping an up-to-date Claude file like this leads to much better code generations.So then, now that we have this file, let's ask Claude Code to do something and see if it sticks to the guidance.
如果不更新，Claude Code 可能無法自動偵測到這些變更，在你要求它執行某些操作時可能會偏離方向。無論如何，這個 CLAUDE.md 檔案現在會自動加入作業階段上下文，讓 Claude 在進行修改時可以參考它。你會發現，保持這份 Claude 檔案的最新狀態，能夠帶來品質更好的程式碼生成結果。既然我們有了這個檔案，讓我們請 Claude Code 做些事情，看看它是否能遵循這份指引。
So, what I would like Claude Co to do for us is make a new hook, which is going to store the user's theme preference based on whatever theme they have when they toggle that little icon in the top right-hand corner.Now, I noticed that inside the Claude file over here, we don't reference a hooked folder.So this would be a good opportunity to just update this file so that ClaudeCode knows where to create hooks.So I'm gonna save this inside the project structure bit right here where it says all hooks, reusable hooks go inside this hooks folder.
我想讓 Claude Code 建立一個新的 Hook，用來儲存使用者的主題偏好，也就是他們切換右上角小圖示時所選的主題。我注意到 CLAUDE.md 檔案中並沒有提到 hooks 資料夾，所以這是個好機會來更新這個檔案，讓 Claude Code 知道應該在哪裡建立 Hook。我要在專案結構的段落中加入：所有可重複使用的 Hook 都放在 hooks 資料夾中。
So now, if I ask ClaudeCode to make a hook, hopefully it's gonna place it inside that folder.All right then, so you can see we don't actually have a hooks folder at the moment, but hopefully Claude Code will create that as well.I'm going to open up the terminal and then I'm going to ask it to create this new hook.I will say, can you create a hook to store the user's theme preference in when they toggle the theme on the site?
現在，如果我請 Claude Code 建立一個 Hook，它應該會把它放在那個資料夾裡。你可以看到我們目前其實還沒有 hooks 資料夾，希望 Claude Code 也會自動建立它。我要打開終端機，請它建立這個新的 Hook，輸入：「你能建立一個 Hook，在使用者切換網站主題時儲存他們的主題偏好嗎？」
And I will say store the value in local storagenext time.
另外我也會說：「將數值儲存在 localStorage 中。」
And then I'm also going to say don't use the hook anywhere yet.Because Claude code has this habit of if it creates a new feature, hook, component, whatever it might be, it wants to use that hook somewhere in your project.So a lot of the time I add this at the end to make sure it doesn't do that.So I'm going to press enter.The only thing I'm really concerned with at the moment is to test whether Claude code looks at that Claude.md file and creates the hook in the correct folder.
我還會加上：「先不要在任何地方使用這個 Hook。」因為 Claude Code 有個習慣：每當它建立新的功能、Hook 或元件，它就會想在專案的某個地方使用它。所以我很多時候會在最後加上這句話，確保它不這樣做。按 Enter 後，我目前最關心的是：Claude Code 是否有看 CLAUDE.md 檔案，並在正確的資料夾中建立 Hook。
Okay, so it looks like it's come up with some code.And if we take a look at this over here, you can see it wants to place it inside the hooks folder.So if we open this up a little bit, this is the hook it's created right here.And again, I'm not going to examine the code too much.I would normally, if this was something I was working on, I would definitely examine the code.But for now, I'm just going to say yes.I'm going to accept that change.
好的，它已經產生了一些程式碼。你可以看到，它想把它放在 hooks 資料夾裡，這正是我們要的。打開來看，這就是它建立的 Hook。同樣地，我現在不會仔細審查程式碼，但如果這是我正在開發的功能，我一定會仔細看。目前我就直接選是，接受這個變更。
And you can see it's created the hooks folder and it's created the use theme file within the folder.Awesome.You can also add a memory to the Claude MD file directly from the chat session by using a hash symbol.For example, I could add a hash, then say something like, when making new page components, always add a link to that page in the header.
可以看到它建立了 hooks 資料夾，並在資料夾中建立了 useTheme 檔案，太棒了。你也可以在聊天作業階段中直接使用井字號（#）將記憶新增到 CLAUDE.md 檔案。例如，我可以加上 # 然後說：「建立新頁面元件時，一律在標題列中加入該頁面的連結。」
And you can see down here as I type that it's telling us it's going to memorize what we're telling it because we added that hash.And the long and short of that is that it's going to place this instruction inside the claw.md file for future reference, so that now, whenever it creates a page component, it should hopefully create a header link for it too.Now, when we hit enter, we're going to see a few options.We can save it to project memory, which is into the Claude.md file we just created for this project.
你可以看到，當我輸入時，下方的提示告訴我們它會記住我們說的內容，因為我們加了井字號。簡而言之，它會將這條指令記錄到 CLAUDE.md 檔案中供未來參考，這樣往後每當它建立頁面元件時，應該也會自動在標題列建立連結。按 Enter 後，我們會看到幾個選項：我們可以將它儲存到專案記憶，也就是我們剛才為這個專案建立的 CLAUDE.md 檔案中。
You could save it to local project memory in the same root folder, but with the.local part added to the file name.And you can also save it to global memory, which is to a global Claude file stored in the root Claude folder on your computer, which the installation added for us.So project memory is what gets set up when we run the /init command to create this claude.nd file in the root of the project.
你也可以將它儲存到本地專案記憶，存放在同一個根目錄資料夾中，但檔案名稱會加上 .local 後綴。還可以儲存到全域記憶，也就是存放在電腦根目錄 Claude 資料夾中的全域 Claude 檔案，這是安裝時自動建立的。專案記憶就是我們執行 /init 指令時在專案根目錄建立的那個 CLAUDE.md 檔案。
And this file is meant to be tracked by version control and pushed to your remote repository so that any other developers working on the project have the same Claude file with the same guidance for Claude code for this project.And that means any memories or information in this file should be specific to the project.For example, folder structure, naming conventions, tests, frameworks, et cetera.
這個檔案應該要納入版本控制並推送到遠端儲存庫，這樣所有共同開發這個專案的開發者都能擁有相同的 Claude 檔案，並獲得相同的 Claude Code 使用指引。這意味著這個檔案中的任何記憶或資訊都應該專屬於這個專案，例如：資料夾結構、命名慣例、測試方式、框架等等。
The local project memory is a file meant for your own personal guidance and preferences when it comes to working with Claude code.So for example, outlining any kind of personal tooling you might use isn't necessarily something other developers working on the same project would use.And this file wouldn't be pushed to the remote repository and it would just be local to you inside this project.And finally, user memory is your personal guidance to Claude when it comes to all projects you work on.
本地專案記憶是一個供你個人使用的檔案，記錄你在使用 Claude Code 時的個人偏好和習慣設定。例如，你可能使用一些其他開發者不一定會用的個人工具，這類說明就適合放在這裡。這個檔案不會推送到遠端儲存庫，只存在於你本機的這個專案中。最後，使用者記憶是你對 Claude 的個人指引，適用於你所有的開發專案。
So, any tools you use globally across many projects or any personal code style preferences that you have would go in that file, and again, this would just be for you on your computer, but it would be for every project that Claude Code runs in.For now, we're just going to add this to the project memory, meaning it should get added to the Claude.md file that we already have.So if I close this off and open this file up, we should be able to see at the bottom that new memory has been added.
因此，你在多個專案中全局使用的工具，或你個人的程式碼風格偏好，都可以放入那個檔案，且同樣只限於你自己的電腦，但會適用於 Claude Code 運行的每個專案。目前，我們只是把這條指令新增到專案記憶，也就是新增到我們已有的 CLAUDE.md 檔案中。關閉對話框，開啟這個檔案後，應該可以在底部看到新增的記憶。
And you can see it right here, when making new page components, always add a link to that page in the header.Awesome.All right, so now we're going to test this out.So I'm going to open Claude Code backup and I'm going to paste in a prompt which says, can you add a new about page with only an H2 title and a single line of Lorem as content.So press enter.Hopefully it's going to read that instruction in the Claude.md file as well and create a link for us.
你可以在這裡看到它：「建立新頁面元件時，一律在標題列中加入該頁面的連結。」太棒了。好的，現在我們來測試一下。我要重新開啟 Claude Code，貼上提示：「你能新增一個只有 H2 標題和一行 Lorem 文字內容的關於（About）頁面嗎？」按 Enter，希望它也能讀取 CLAUDE.md 檔案中的那條指令，並自動為我們建立連結。
And you can see in its to-dos, it says right here, add about page link to the header navigation.So it knows about that.All right, so I'm just gonna accept these changes.Again, normally you should check this, but for the sake of this tutorial, I'm just gonna accept this.And again, it's asking for permission to edit the file, the layout file this time to add the new link.Again, I'm gonna press yes, you can do this.And then another change to the layout file, which I'm gonna accept as well.Okay, and now it's done.
你可以在它的待辦清單中看到：「將關於頁面連結新增到標題列導覽」，所以它知道這條指令。好的，我就接受這些變更，平時你應該要仔細檢查，但為了教學流程，我就直接接受了。它請求修改版面檔案（layout 檔）以新增連結，我選是允許；然後又有一個對版面檔案的修改，我也接受。好了，現在完成了。
So if I close this off, open up app, and then we can see this about page.And inside there, we have an H2 title and just a single line of Lorem Ipsum Awesome, and then if we go to the layout page, which it's edited, hopefully it's added a link right here, so it's added it to this nav, so it says About right here.Now, let's try this out in a browser.Okay, so yes, it has done that.You can see the about link here, and if we click on that, we go to the about page.
關閉後開啟應用程式，可以看到這個關於頁面，裡面有一個 H2 標題和一行 Lorem Ipsum 文字，太棒了。接著前往它編輯過的版面頁面，可以看到它在導覽列中加入了「About」連結。現在在瀏覽器中試試看，確實完成了！你可以看到這裡有 About 連結，點擊後就會跳轉到關於頁面。
You can see also, retrospectively, it's added these other two links, which I didn't ask it to do.This is one of the things I've noticed about Claude Code sometimes.Like I mentioned before, it sometimes likes to do things beyond the scope of what you've asked it to do.It is important to maybe tell Claude Code, look, don't do this, just do this.That could be something you add to your Claude.md file.
你也可以看到，它還額外加入了另外兩個連結，但這是我沒有要求的。這是我注意到 Claude Code 有時會有的習慣：就像我之前提到的，它有時喜歡做超出你要求範圍的事情。這時候很重要的是要明確告訴 Claude Code：「不要做這個，只做這個就好。」這也可以作為一條指引加到你的 CLAUDE.md 檔案中。
Now, just really quickly, I do want to mention that on the Claude code docs, they say that the local memory is being deprecated in favor of importing untracked files within the project level memory to provide that personal context to Claude.And I'll show you how to import a reference files later in the course.But at the time of recording this video, the local option still shows in the terminal when you use the memory hashtag shortcut to add new memories.
在這裡順帶一提，在 Claude Code 的官方文件中，他們表示本地記憶將被棄用，改為在專案層級記憶中匯入未追蹤的檔案來提供個人化上下文。我會在課程後面示範如何匯入參考檔案。但在錄製這部影片時，使用記憶井字號快捷方式新增記憶時，本地選項仍然會出現在終端機中。
Another way you can access your memory files is by using the memory command, which is just forward slash memory.And by the way, if it isn't already obvious, when I say memory files, I'm just talking about the Claude.md files, whether they're project, local, or global.But anyway...When you use this memory command, Claude code is going to ask you which memory file you want to open and edit.So you can select any of these and press enter to open that file up.
另一個存取記憶檔案的方式是使用 /memory 指令。順帶說明，當我提到「記憶檔案」時，只是在說 CLAUDE.md 檔案，無論它是專案級、本地或全域的。使用 /memory 指令後，Claude Code 會詢問你想要開啟並編輯哪個記憶檔案，選擇其中一個並按 Enter 即可開啟該檔案。
For example, if I select the project memory, it's going to open up the Claude.md file right here in VS Code so that I can edit it directly myself.So then just to summarize, it's always good practice to use the forward slash init command when you bring Claude code into a project, because it gives Claude the chance to learn about the code base and outline any structural patterns, frameworks, libraries, naming conventions, et cetera, in a Claude file.That file is then used by Claude as contact automatically when it makes decisions about your project in the future.
例如，如果我選擇專案記憶，它會在 VS Code 中開啟 CLAUDE.md 檔案，讓我可以直接自行編輯。總結一下：在將 Claude Code 引入專案時，最好的做法是使用 /init 指令，因為它讓 Claude 有機會了解程式碼庫，並將架構模式、框架、函式庫、命名慣例等資訊記錄到 CLAUDE.md 檔案中。Claude 之後在對你的專案做決策時，會自動將這個檔案作為上下文使用。
And it can be added to your remote repository so that other developers working on the project have access to it as well for their own workflow using Claude code.Finally, it's not something you should just create and then forget about, but rather keep on top of, edit and update when things change within your project.That way, you're always keeping Claude in the loop and you'll find its work to be much more in line with your project's existing current code and structure.
它也可以新增到你的遠端儲存庫，讓其他共同開發這個專案的開發者在使用 Claude Code 時也能取得這份指引。最後，這個檔案不是建立後就可以置之不理的，而是需要持續關注、在專案發生變更時進行編輯和更新。這樣才能讓 Claude 始終掌握最新的專案狀態，你會發現它的輸出內容與你專案現有的程式碼和結構會更加一致。